Rakib Raihan Fahim

**** +880 1305 642 784

fahim098.netlify.app

☑ rfahim098@gmail.com

https://github.com/RyanFahim

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rrfahim/

Panasree, Dhaka



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Persistent, detailed-oriented, and enthusiastic software engineer having expertise in web development, MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js), and problem-solving. Highly motivated to join an organization to enhance skills and strengthen knowledge in the related field, along with contributing to the organization's growth.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Ultra-X BD

June 2022 - Present

Responsible For

- Software Development
- Software evaluation and testing
- Research and inspection technology.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant at East West University

January 2019 - July 2021

Responsible For

- Assisting teachers with lesson preparation by preparing materials and setting up equipment.
- Revise lesson material with students individually or in small groups.
- Document student progress

PROJECTS

Drutology: A new system to measure customer's experience in Bangladesh | github.com/RyanFahim/Drutology Key responsibilities of the project:

A mobile application developed with Android Studio captures network parameters to provide a good network experience that can capture network signal value and user's location, measure download speed in that area, and store it in a central database. Propose a decent and efficient way to analyze the network type and download speed in a particular site.

Geritch Restaurant | github.com/RyanFahim/gerich-restaurant

Key responsibilities of the project:

A modern & fully responsive website that can be used for restaurants

Live preview: https://geritch-rrf.netlify.app/

Movie-mania | github.com/RyanFahim/Movie-mania

Key responsibilities of the project:

A live website to search movies and individual movies information

Live preview: https://moviemania-rrf.netlify.app/

Snake game | github.com/RyanFahim/Snake game

Key responsibilities of the project:

A simple snake game developed by javascript. Can be played in pc

Live preview: https://snakegamebyfahim.netlify.app/

Weather App | github.com/RyanFahim/Weather_app

Key responsibilities of the project:

A simple weather app to search weather by city names developed by React JS

Live preview: https://weatherscan.netlify.app/

Student Result Management System | github.com/RyanFahim/Student-Result-Management-System

Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with PHP that manages the details of results, activities, courses, and exams and results.

Handwritten Character Recognition with Motion Detection |

github.com/RyanFahim/Handwritten-Character-Recognition-with-Motion-Detection Key responsibilities of the project:

A system developed with Machine Learning that can identify characters using motion detection.

More Projects

Visit GitHub or my portfolio website to explore more projects.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Ethical Hacker | November 2021 - November 2024. License ECC2615387094

COMPUTER SKILL

Programming Language: JavaScript, React JS, Node.js, HTML, CSS, GitHub

Frameworks: Next.js, Express.js **Database:** MongoDB, MySql

Operating System: Windows 7, 8.1 & 10, Linux,

Hardware: Comprehensive knowledge of computer hardware.

Interests: Web Development, CSS animation, and making large-scale websites

ACCOMPLISHMENT

Merit scholarship in East West University | January 2018 - January 2019 Dean's scholarship in East West University | January 2019 - January 2020

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering | January 2017 - July 2021 | East West University

CGPA: 3.50 on a Scale of 4.00

Thesis: Drutology: A new system to measure customer's experience in Bangladesh

H.S.C from Science Group | March 2014 - July 2016 | Govt. Sundarban Adarsha College, Khulna

GPA: 4.75 on a Scale of 5.00

STRENGTH

Good analytical and problem-solving skills, Team player, and Strong interpersonal skills with a great work ethic.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Bangla (Native), English (Proficient in communicating and writing)

REFERENCES

Ashikur Rahman

Territory Manager,

VMware Bangladesh

Email: rashikur@vmware.com Cell: +880 1713 201 885